Aldo Munaretto

+34 635096305

aldomunaretto@gmail.com

in aldomunaretto 🖸 aldomunaretto

Madrid,ES

Work Experience

Data Scientist

August 2018 - present

Finect

- Development of ETL processes for the integration of different data sources for their subsequent exploitation and analysis.
- Design and development of KPIs for reports and dashboards.
- Creation of predictive models for the optimization of programmatic advertising campaigns.
- Implementation of user segmentation and profiling models to offer personalized content and improve the user experience.
- Optimize joint development efforts through proper use of the databases and project design
- Development of recommendation algorithms for articles, topics, tags, etc.
- Analysis of actions and user behavior to improve the recommendations engines.
- Use of Machine Learning and Deep Learning techniques for the development of new solutions or optimization of existing ones.
- Development of microservices for the integration of predictive models in the company's production environment.
- Continuous deployment and automation of routine processes..
- Tools: Python, PySpark, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB, ElasticSearch), Kibana, Kafka, git, Docker, Jenkins, Rundeck, Power Bl.

PHP Developer

March 2018 - July 2018

Finect

- Development of software and web pages for internal consumption of the company.
- Tools: PHP, MySQL, HTML5, CSS3.

Education

Saturdays.Al

February 2019 - May 2019

Artificial Intelligence's Bootcamp (Deep Learning)

Content: Transfer Learning, Deep Neural Networks (DNN), Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN), Generative Adversarial Networks (GAN), Natural Language Processing (NLP) y Computer Vision.

Final Project: Bookanimation. Use of generative adversarial networks (GANs) to create animated characters based on the text of children's stories. Winner of the "Closest to State of the Art" award.

Datahack School

October 2017 - May 2018

Master in Big Data & Analytics

Content: Data Discovery, Machine Learning with Python, Machine Learning with SAS, NoSQL Databases, Hadoop ecosystem, Apache Spark, Data visualization, Advanced algorithms with Python.

Projects: Use of ML algorithms to determine the optimal prediction model for binary classification, multiclass classification and regression. Text sentiment analysis for Amazon's Reviews. Fraud detection with different statistical models using SAS-Miner, Movie Recommender (Collaborative Filter with Spark ML), Classification of photographs using convolutional networks (CNN).

Universitat de Barcelona

April 2017 - June 2018

Master in Business Intelligence

Content: Data Management and the Information Society, Strategic management and BI systems, Decision Support Systems, Business Analytics, Big Data and Digital Business Transformation, Business Intelligence project management, Evaluation and Selection of BI Tools (Case Study MS Power Pivot), Data Mining and The Role of the Data Scientist, Data Discovery (Practice with Qlik Sense), CRM & Business Intelligence. Master's thesis: BI platform for the Intendancy of the Department of Canelones, Uruguay.

About Me

I am a data scientist and software developer focused on finding solutions based on data analysis. I have experience developing scalable data science projects and applying machine learning techniques to complex datasets. My interest is to cover the entire data's life cycle in any real project, from the architecture to the analysis and the final presentation to the client, providing the best solution at every step.

Skills

| Programming Languages |
|---|
| Python SQL R PHP |
| |
| • Frameworks & Tools |
| NumPy Pandas Scikit-Learn Jenkins |
| Flask Spark Kafka Docker |
| |
| Deep Learning |
| Keras TensorFlow Pytorch Fastai |
| |
| • NLP |
| NLTK Gensim Spacy Transformers |
| |
| • BBDD |
| PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB |
| ElasticSearch |
| |

Soft Skills

- Complex problem solving
- · Critical Thinking
- Teamwork
- Adaptability and fast learning

Languages

- Spanish: Native or Bilingual
- English: Advance Full Professional

Presentations

Machine Learning Spain XLI

Título: "Descubriendo el motor de recomendación de artículos de Finect.com"

[Link]

Interests

